we hit a peak of something like 850 PRs in a week,
and 85, 90% of those were handled by agents entirely.
I bet a lot of people
when they think software factories or agents,
they're sort of expecting a speed up or hoping for a speed
So we've actually seen that now that we have all this extra capacity,
you don't turn all of it towards cranking out new features.
one of the members of my design team, was saying, just put up and landed
13 PRs that were all about fixing consistency, copy
and brand voice and removing borders that weren't supposed to be there.
Things that would have just lingered on a backlog can actually now get done.
The AI Native Dev is a podcast for developers and engineering
leads at the cutting edge of AI and agentic coding.
Join your hosts, Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple,
every week as we chat with the most exciting voices in
AI and tackle the biggest questions facing developers today.
This is the AI Native Dev.
Yesterday you were writing code.
Today you're prompting agents.
Tomorrow you'll be running a software factory.
Agentic coding is moving fast enough to give anyone whiplash.
This June, AI DevCon London sold out. Hundreds of developers,
engineering leads and VP's packed in
to hear speakers from Anthropic, OpenAI, Netlify, and GitHub,
cut through the hype and get to what actually works.
This November, we're bringing it back to New York.
Bigger, bolder, and full of people actually building the agentic future.
Three days of real talks, real tools, real answers.
Whether you're directing the agents, building the loops themselves,
leading the teams, or setting the strategy.
Our early bird pricing ends on September 30th,
so make sure you lock in your place before prices increase.
As a podcast listener, you can get 15% off your ticket using promo code POD15.
We have so much planned and we can't wait to have you
join us in New York.
Hello, everyone.
Welcome back to the AI Native Dev.
Thanks for tuning back in today.
Myself and Dru here, our Head of Product at Tessl.
We wanted to catch you up a little bit on what we've been up to
at Tessl, what we've been building over the last 2 or 3 months.
I think we had a bit of this episode
talking about the Tessl agent, which we'll kind of mention.
A year and a half to get me on the podcast back in three months.
So I'm.
Trying to say I'm so, you know, irresistible sort of.
Once you're. Out like that. You're getting on.
So really, like, there's a lot that we've been
sort of building here at Tessl, but I think the the key thing
we're most excited by is this sort of expansion of Tessl from
just sort of focusing on helping you own your context, right,
and having a skill
registry and build skills correctly and optimize them, which we still think
is like an enormous, important piece of this sort of new
development paradigm to starting to build loops.
We talked about that a little bit with the Tessl agent launch on it to
to now really increasingly thinking about Tessl as a composable factory
or as a platform that helps you build factory.
And we talk about and we'll sort of mention this a lot today.
We talk about how Tessl helps you get to your factory, from skills
to loops to factory,
which is sort of our view of the world of this sort of context centric factory.
Yeah.
So before we we dive into that, we,
we actually released this sort of super fun little mini documentary about.
Yeah, yeah, but Kikimora the the the spirit, the.
It's a European.
Eastern European spirit.
It will clean your house at night.
I'm quoting Maria.
So thank you, Maria, for for letting me know this.
It cleans your house at night, but only if you're good, if you are making
a mess, if you're being disrespectful, it makes things worse.
Which we felt like was a perfect analogy for agents.
Like if you're keeping your house in order, agents give you superpowers.
If you're being irresponsible, they give you anticipate powers, right?
They go through whatever.
You've sort of given them to. Exactly.
Yeah, a little bit of some some Christmas allusions there. Yeah.
I think.
For the naughty list on the so that's the name of our sort of dark factory,
and we have a really fun mini documentary about this
that was very well produced on it, you know, by a friend here,
Tom, who's our, our producer and definitely maybe like 13 minutes
or something like that.
14 minutes.
Definitely a fun watch where committed.
We're not going to force you to sort of repeat the whole thing over here.
But maybe before we dive into the sort of factories and how we build it,
maybe you can just remind us a little bit of Tessl's own
kind of dark factory, what could be built inside, a few words about what?
What is it that that we have and like what the value we're seeing.
That maybe I'll, I'll start very, very briefly.
I feel like every one of these podcasts has to start
with a bit of just like terms.
What do they mean these days? You know, two weeks later.
So really quickly, I think a couple of things.
First, we've mentioned skills loops and factories.
So skills are obviously skills
became quite popular at the beginning of the year.
They've sort of expanded.
Some people will call them plug ins.
Think when we say skills as like a unit of work.
It's either a workflow that you want completed or it is a policy,
a standard that you want agents to adhere to that includes skills.
It also includes things like hooks or MCP tools,
like anything you could bundle in a plugin.
It's just that skills is the most popular term.
It's what everybody thinks of
as the unit for agents, so we sort of use that interchangeably.
Right.
So that's I think one the second is loops.
Think of these as effectively automated skills.
It's things that are running
without immediate human intervention at least to start them.
And then as they run, typically there's some kind of meta process
where the loop is getting better as it runs.
It is making things better for the next run.
And so you start to get compounding gains.
You start to see agents
sort of inflecting your productivity upwards faster than just linear.
Yeah. And this is like the hence the loop. Right.
Because it goes from an agent workflow
to something that loops with some form of learning back into the beginning.
So hopefully the second time around or the hundredth time around is better.
Than the first one, right?
Yeah.
And loops are where you really start to see your first glimmers
of that sort of inflection point or your trajectory really taking off.
And then a factory is in many ways it's a way of working.
It's where you've moved almost all of your development
to the creation and maintenance and monitoring of loops.
And the loops are now what produce most of your software or.
The product.
One way of thinking of this is that your factory will have some code.
That code will largely be loops,
and then your product that you shipped to users is also some code.
Where are your humans spending their time?
When you move to the factory,
you're mostly spending your time maintaining the loops and thinking about
how to make them better.
Yeah, and in a ways, it's like the entirety of your SDLC, right?
If you're a loops are kind of a kind of evolution of your pipelines,
you know, some automation that become now.
So better.
I'm trying to make factory development lifecycle a thing, FDLC.
It hasn't caught on yet,
but we'll see if I get to do a terms segment at the beginning of the next one.
Hopefully that'll. Be one. Maybe the FDLC. Yeah. If.
You have a list.
Like the FDLC versus the SDLC.
So with that, with that as groundwork, what is more, what have we been building?
So Tessl's really
been trying to go on this same journey from the start of the year.
Our development internally was very skills driven to start.
Right.
We wrote down what good looks like, how
we wanted code review to function, how we wanted.
If you're building something
in the CLI versus in the UI, just like writing things down.
And then once we felt like we were in a good place there,
and we'll talk about why we think that's important to to start there,
we then wanted to really get into the business of handing work over to agents.
And so we started thinking about how can we automate more and more
of our tasks so that a human isn't having to click buttons or type
text into a a text box to kick it off?
And we we started that and very quickly,
like the minute you get your first couple loops in place, you start to realize
this is going to get out of hand really quickly
and you have to move to a different way of working
that has a bit more of the solution baked into the problem itself.
And so that was where we made the decision,
like we're going to go full factory, we're going to build out a system where
basically all of our work, all of our PRs are created by agents.
We focus more on shaping work.
So we create issues reviewing work.
So we will look at PRs as they're put up.
Increasingly, we're trying to have agents review more and more of that code,
and we only invest in the sort of like high leverage points.
And then where we're doing our software engineering are observability.
Our monitoring is in the loops themselves.
And so oftentimes you're creating loops to monitor loops
or you are creating dashboards to control plane your loops and things like that.
And so that's been the flow that we've moved to internally at Tessl.
I think the last stat we saw, we hit a peak of something like 850 PRs
in a week, and about 90, 85,
90% of those were handled by agents entirely.
So that's been our journey.
Again, we won't make you
watch the whole documentary again here, but if you're interested, go check it out.
It's a lot of fun.
Yeah, lots of great nuggets for folks to to think about.
And the pace.
I guess maybe what I would add is before we kind of leaned into the factory,
what it felt like was that we had a bunch of high automation environments,
but they were very kind of disparate, you know, environments,
very different developers,
like some some members of the team, first of all, were sort of more,
I guess, into automation and automated their kind of work in
to a large degree, while others were a bit further behind,
just sort of using it in a slightly more sort of standard way.
But then also the ones that were automating
were automating their work and iterating, and it was quite siloed.
So I think the factory is also a bit of that
path to go from single player to multiplayer, right? Totally.
And go into that collaboration.
And I think from like from a security lens perspective.
There's also the advantage that once you start running things in the cloud
and in kind of these defined workflows, then then you start
kind of having visibility
to it, you know, what's installed, you can identify risks and contain them.
You know, you can you can create more protected environment.
It's a transparent system as well. You can observe everything.
Yeah, exactly.
And I've a I'm one of those who who thought the cloud IDEs
will catch on a lot sooner.
It's like.
They're. Just they're just better, like, you know, you have a strong.
Machine behind there and you can work from any spot on it and you can do it.
And lo and behold, they, they didn't really like they're used somewhat.
But there's all these advantages,
I think as you get into agentic workflows
and really you're interacting through chats, I mean, developers
machines look more like The Matrix and kind of the stereotypical, you know,
hacker in movies in the for did before then, then I think.
It makes.
Sense and we're seeing I guess I will add maybe with the management hat on on it
is that we're seeing some incredible speed on it.
Again, there's a bunch of stats
that we mentioned in a variety of spots and in the, in the movie.
But you know, we're seeing just sort of compounding paces.
And now increasingly indeed the org is leaning into it.
And more of the GTM is in it.
I think maybe if I could add one quick the sort of increased feature velocity.
Great to see it's the one you sort of are targeting.
I bet a lot of people when they think software factories or agents,
they're sort of expecting a speed up or hoping for a speed up.
Two of the things that we've seen that were interesting,
I may not have guessed up front for the big one was an increase in quality.
So we've actually seen that now that we have all this extra capacity,
you don't turn all of it towards cranking out new features.
Some of it,
like one of the members of my design team, was saying, I just put up and landed
13 PRs that were all about fixing consistency and
copy and brand voice and removing borders that weren't supposed to be there.
Things that would have just lingered on a backlog can actually now get done.
And then the other one is just better. Fungibility.
Like people, fungibility is maybe such a boring business
way of saying it, but everyone is able to do a little bit of everything, right?
Like I just mentioned, a designer putting up PRs that are getting merged.
But also our GTM team is able to make changes to the marketing website
without waiting on support from engineering.
Engineering can write their own specs.
You just have this ability for people to work on whatever's high leverage
and not thinking about, like, who's ready to pick this up?
How can I hand it off all. Of that? Right.
And I think so factories are in vogue.
Yeah.
Like you hear a lot of companies talking about sort of their their path to it.
And I think that's exciting.
This is the new development paradigm.
And at the same time, there's sort of this world of skepticism
around being able to, you know, produce quality software.
Is a. Process and is it ready?
And a lot of sentiment of how you move from the bottleneck
being the production of the code to being the review of the code,
and is the code that's being generated any good?
And at Tessl we've long seen the world through this
sort of lens of, of specs and context and skills.
Right.
Like our kind of roots are very much around start by defining spec.
So what is it that you want to do.
And we have this core conviction that to to automate the thing you first
have to sit down and do this bit that is, you know, defining what correct is.
What is it that you want to do. Right.
And I would use, I think, since the beginning of
this example of saying, hey, what do you want for your birthday?
It's like, I don't know, you decide, you know, like vibe.
It on. It and you may or may not be happy with it.
You know, if you know, use that sort of approach to buy you every year.
You know, that gift. You know, some of them will be disappointments.
And I think I think this is what we're seeing with with a bunch of that software.
And so we, we think of context as the, as the core, right, as the sort of manual
for operating your company, operating your workflows,
you know, a bunch of those definitions.
And, and when we when we talk about building the factory,
we have this perspective on how a factory should work,
which is that it should be context centric, right?
It should.
And hence the sort of repeated terms of going from skills to loops to factory.
And, and it was interesting to, to sort of see that manifest in code.
So a couple of months ago or so we launched a little over.
We launched the Tessl agent. Right.
The Tessl agent kind of helps you build build loops.
You know, there was a core part of it.
You run it and it helps you find automations
and improvements and optimizations in your system and starts creating a loop
that will sort of run that and kind of make it go again and again.
And we had someone on our on our team, Tom,
build an automation that says like, okay, let's let's build.
I forget actually the specific workflow.
I think it was it was around.
Test coverage or something in that domain and created
that workflow with sort of plain vanilla Claude and with Tessl
and with sort of another sort of factory related agent out there.
And what what we saw was that these sort of two other ones,
they actually built the solution, the cookie cutter solution,
a little bit faster because they just sort of wrote a whole pile of code,
like a lot of that output of that process was creating code
that just created the pipeline to run a bunch of those sort of tests,
right, and, and run the process around them.
While the approach that the Tessl agent takes
and was almost unintentional is just sort of our world view,
our sort of a, our view on kind of this domain was first, it created
this sort of chain of logic like this is the definition of what correct is.
This is sort of the specs of how it would work, and then it built on top of it.
And so it was it was a much more context driven
workflow, which on one hand took a moment longer and it was stronger.
And some things it was more resilient, more malleable,
and could find more cases and make them work at the same time.
You know, it, it, it it again was a little bit more effort,
but it was more resilient now to be able to evolve and to and to grow.
So this sort of context centricity was so ingrained in how we build.
There was a
so this is like a little bit of like I liked that story
because it sort of naturally emerged from how we think about the world.
And I think you, you, you had a similar view.
When we think about that context centricity,
when it comes to code review on it, maybe you can say a few.
Words about that.
I think that code review is actually a both a good example
of how context centricity is sort of crucial,
but it's also hopefully one that hits close to home for folks.
So maybe to start with the way most people
will adopt some form of a code review.
There's a bunch of great tools out there that make it really easy to get started.
You install a GitHub app, or you click a few buttons here and there
and it's boom!
You've now got agents reviewing your PRs, you're finding bugs,
you're maybe merging faster, or you're at least catching more issues.
And it feels great.
It's kind of like this dopamine hit.
As is so often the case with AI,
it's so easy to get to that first demo or that first wow moment.
How do you scale it from there?
And what a lot of people see is that amazing?
I'm doing agentic code review.
Like I'm really I'm living it.
And then a couple weeks later they find, well,
okay, like we're finding a few more bugs
or maybe merging a bit faster, but nothing's changing after that.
Like we we got a small boost, but it's not this exponential like compounding gains.
It's just like a small improvement.
And again, we're stuck again.
Right? It still feels like code quality is a problem.
Or like PR review is still an issue.
And yeah, the Tessl philosophy is because you're hitting this wall
because you jumped past the,
you know, you tried to get to the the big muscles without working out,
or you tried to get healthy without eating your vegetables.
There is a certain amount of you have to write down what good looks like.
You have to know, like, what do I care about?
how does quality in the code base manifest?
And if you don't do that, if you skip past,
you just have a tool that says like, don't worry, I'll handle it.
I'll review the code for you.
You will eventually hit a problem where two big ones.
The first is that, well, now you you'd like to use those standards
elsewhere, right?
Like code review is good for catching things at the end.
But really, what you'd like to do, especially to help with costs or to
get features develop faster, is while building the feature,
you'd like the agent
to also see your standards and make sure that it is writing code
in the correct way, and not everything is going to get caught by code review.
So you'd also like to have regular automations that sweep
your code base and say, is there anything that's not conforming to our standards
that slip through or somehow is accrued and we need to fix and pull back?
So you need all the like, you want to use it in multiple places,
and if you haven't written it down, you can't do that.
You can't reuse it
or say you have a new project, somebody creating a new app or testing a prototype.
It's in a different repo.
How do you translate
your standards over to them so they can get started right away?
And so there's this one, there's this, this enormous benefit in writing it down
and being able to share it.
But also when you write it down, it becomes much easier to reason
about and improve it and to even have specialized versions
for different parts of the code base.
So you want to say in this area, our standards are this,
you know, like for the front end, we care a lot about ARIA attributes
and accessibility and having the right sort of nesting of borders.
But when when it's a back end PR, none of that matters, right?
Don't waste time. Don't waste tokens.
Focus instead on, you know, brittleness or sort of reusing certain components.
And in fact, this specificity, being able to tune exactly what you're
reviewing becomes increasingly important as you move towards factory.
Because really, the volume of factory is going to put out
you you have to get humans out of the loop for code review.
And a general purpose code review is not going to get to 100% quality
like you have to be able to say for this component,
here's all the things you need to check.
You have to get really specific
and you just can't do that if you're not writing.
It down.
Hey everyone.
My name is Sahil and I'm one of the engineers here at Tessl.
I'm going to be in New York and in Boston on the 16th and 17th of September,
talking about how we've built our software factory here at Tessl
and what engineering looks like in an AI native world.
I'm going to be diving in to the components that we've built out,
why they're there, why they're useful, the mistakes that we've made along the way,
the sort of metrics that we focused on early
that actually didn't end up helping us, and the ones that actually did
in all the different quirks and features that ended up building out the factory
that we have today,
this is going to be a much more practical look into the factory
that we have here at Tessl, and some of the specifics on how it works
and why we made some of the decisions that we did. Go to tessl.io/events.
And I hope to see you all there.
I think so.
Really kind of a good articulation of the view
that you have to kind of capture and define
what correct is, what correct looks like,
and then you can do that at the granularity that you want.
Sometimes it is shared across the different parts. Of.
The of the of the product stack.
You might want it in review and encoding.
Maybe you want it across repos and sometimes it's the other way around.
It kind of gets more granular as well in this subfolder.
You know, when Dru writes code,
we want to make sure
that you sort of check, you know, that he doesn't again do X, you know.
Or whatever. Exactly.
So I think I think the sort of core is a really good story of it
and an example of, of a loop that you can improve
because indeed a factory has to sort of go to.
A yeah.
You have to sort of drive towards higher autonomy,
and that has to sort of come with sort of definition of. Of.
What's correct, hence kind of skill centric.
So I think let's, let's shift a little bit
and talk about some of the capabilities that,
that we're sort of excited by in it.
And because we talk
about the journey from, from, from skills to loops to, to to factory,
maybe we'll start with a little bit over the last sort of two, 2 to 3 months on it.
What sort of what's been sort of interesting
in the skills part of it, of the product, you know, what's what's been launching.
How do you capture.
What's good, what the workflows are, etc..
So I think last time we checked in, Tessl agent was a big part of this.
We talked about how you could use it to create loops that themselves
turn back and help you find new contexts and things that you want to write down.
Since then, we've added a big feature that we've been calling
Skills Inventory, Context Inventory.
So what this is, is a command line as well as a GitHub app
that you can install across your your source estate.
So across all your repos and we will scan and find
all instances of context that's being fed to agents.
So the most common form here is skills.
But it could also be other like AGENTS.md files
or plugin marketplaces things like this.
And then we just help you reason about it.
So we give you a bunch of findings around do you have out of date context.
Right.
We can detect oh, you've installed this skill from Anthropic Marketplace.
It's now four versions behind.
Do you want to update to the most recent version?
We can do the same thing internally, right?
Like, hey, we have found this same skill in five different places.
It seems like this is actually the source where it's being maintained.
Do you want to link
all of those downstream versions to this and then get them up to date?
But we can also find things like duplicate context, where multiple
people have been solving the same problem and not realizing it.
And we can help you
standardize on one so that you can then start improving it for everyone.
We also look on stale things where maybe you wrote a skill
about how to contribute to the back end, and now the code has drifted away
from the skill itself.
We can help you identify that and get it up to date.
And this is a capability we're going to keep investing in
where we're just continually scanning your code estate.
We're finding all of the context that agents are using.
We're pulling it out and we're telling you
how can it be improved, how could it be reused shared.
And so that's an area that we'll keep improving.
But the sort of duplicate stale.
Or in general, just finding things where there's opportunities
to improve the overall performance and quality of your critical
skills is a big improvement we've made to the platform.
Yeah, yeah.
I think it's been interesting to see how how deep the inventory capability.
We thought it was a. Quick feature and it. Just it started.
Like, yeah, we'll just sort of files in your repos and I'll find all the.
Ones that. Are called X.
And then okay, we'll sort of run a review on all of those.
We already had the skill review. So we'll we'll score them.
We'll sort of say are there any good, you know, doing it.
And then from there you get into indeed there's like well these,
these look like they do the same.
It's amazing how unimaginative.
We are when we think about.
Sort of. Ideas.
For for skills on it.
Like a lot a lot of duplicates, which makes sense.
But then that creates problems.
It's not just wasteful because the knowledge doesn't accumulate in one spot.
It again creates kind of inconsistency and misalignment in the systems.
How do you drive that once you created those?
There's all this question about,
well, when people use a skill, how do they discover the right one?
How do you do it?
So we added the whole kind of recommended skills that nudges you
to sort of use the right ones.
Yeah, I guess security has been there for a while, you know, around
sort of assessing whether those skills are sort of trustworthy and doing it
and it just sort of goes, goes on and on around action ability, the dynamics
between the platform team that is found maybe done, that broad scan
and the sort of the people that own the repos.
Yeah.
Inventory is kind of become an entry point to all of the tools
that, you know, you've know and love for Tessl, right.
Like security policies, governance, being able to require, hey, these skills
like our brand voice or our code review needs to be in every repo.
Now we can help you find those skills and set up those policies.
So it kind of becomes the integral control plane for somebody
who's thinking about how do we manage skills across our organization.
Yeah.
And I think, you know, I can't avoid the sort of the analysis,
the security world I kind of came from, which is, you know, it's Snyk.
It was very much around,
hey, Will, scan all your repos, we'll find all your dependencies.
And it was similarly like a very deep.
Kind of.
Tunnel over there to go to sort of say which ones are vulnerable.
But you get that sort of instant visibility, cloud security,
posture management, or CSPM tools like Wiz, you know, are sort of known for that.
So I think it's similar.
And then I think we've also done
a bunch of stuff on the the quality aspect of the skills.
We've started building, kind of capturing of logs.
And we built these sort of verifiers.
Do want to maybe say a couple of words on that and then we'll kind of go. To loops.
Yeah, yeah.
And also, I'd be remiss if I didn't also mention
we've extended support beyond just engineering use cases.
So now we have the ability once we've inventoried all your context you can now
version distribute deploy
for your go to market function, for sales for support for anything like that.
So that's been a big boost.
You know we're using it internally as well.
Yeah. I.
Like the I think I'm kind of especially fond
right now of the, the synchronization with the marketplace. Yes.
Because I feel people on one hand like the convenience
of the Claude marketplace and just sort of pushes it, you know.
To, to Cowork.
Or to others, then they don't really want to be beholden to to Anthropic, you know,
what about the, you know, the kind of OpenAI kind of ChatGPT marketplaces.
What brings places? Yeah.
So managing the sort of the skills centrally
on the sort of the Tessl registry and then synchronizing them
to the right spots has been quite appealing.
All the benefits being model agnostic, having an actual
like versioned lifecycle, seeing prevent regressions, all of that.
Yeah. Now comes for your non devs as well.
And in a nice smooth experience where you don't need to teach your
your sales team get workflows or or anything like that.
So yeah, on top of that, we're starting to explore from our own factory.
A lot of what we build comes from first, what did we need ourselves
to make context driven factories work inside of Tessl.
And one of the big things we found is that
skills really are
the code of a workflow of what good looks like.
And that's great.
That's sort of like the interface where you want to write down,
this is what's important, this is how agents will look at it.
But everybody wants that little bit of extra security, extra
surety, like, yes, I wrote it down, but agents don't have to follow markdown.
So did it did it actually do that?
And so verifiers are a thing we've built at Tessl.
You can think of it as a way of turning your skills into
or creating off of them very focused,
high accuracy, very fast, very cheap.
LLM as judge tools.
Where to take an example, let's say you have a skill
that says all front end components must have ARIA attributes on them.
Right? We can generate from that a verifier.
This is a very simple case, but we generate a verifier
that says for every TSX file or JSX file that's changed, we want to scan
all React components and say do they have ARIA attributes on them?
It's like a very simple prompt.
Then LLM judge can be very small,
very cheap and get it right effectively all the time.
So fast, so cheap that you can actually run it in CI if you'd like.
And in fact, that's what we do here at Tessl.
And so as a result it basically gives you the enforcement half of a skill.
So you write out what is good look like what is success.
And then we generate these verifiers that you can then put up in CI/CD
so that you know your skills are being followed.
And so that's a tool that we are increasingly relying on where
I think we're working right now on the ability to say,
as soon as you create a skill, we'll create verifiers for it
so that you can enforce the skill in a way that feels deterministic.
Right?
It moves us back towards the world we're used to in software development.
Yeah, yeah.
And I think I very much
see this as the trust but verify, you know, like you run the agent,
you give them instructions, you trust them, you have to let go to some extent.
You know, for them to do that.
But then you build these verifiers and indeed I like the, the speed
and in general, like verifiers are still still forming,
you know,
but they can check this sort of the agent actions against the sort of the logs,
they can check the output of it, of what has he done,
they can be deterministic or they can be judge.
And I think they I think there will be a core fundamental
going alongside in a skill, the context of what you want it to do.
Verifiers are, you know, the checks to say has it actually done it.
And I think that is very powerful.
And I think maybe we do need to get to loops,
but maybe they have few words, which is we've also seen a bit
of a revived interest in evals.
Evals have kind of been a little bit more the, the purist domain.
You know, the people like people were vibing it, you know. To.
The extent and I think what has happened is the world has matured enough
and people have come across those cases where they where they have a challenge.
And I think it might feel a little bit scary to people as we talk
about, hey, you have to sit down and write down all of your paths.
But I think one of the key unlocks that we've embraced,
probably starting about three months ago, is, is this appreciation that a lot of
that correctness can actually be extracted from historical behavior?
It just then
needs to be codified and captured, and then you need to iterate on it.
So, so verifiers evals are increasingly even in the Tessl
agent example extracted out of historical activity.
So it's not that it's a real burden that you need to sit down and write down,
you know.
Kind of.
Painfully all of those instructions.
But it's, you know,
if there's a thing that you are reviewing, if there's a thing that you own,
it really should be these domains of your instructions.
And the more you review and trust that sort of instruction set
and those verifiers, the more autonomy
you can give the agents as they operate and the more value.
You get. Right?
And yeah,
I think it's just worth pointing out that that the Tessl agent exists to try
and make it not feel like going to the gym or eating your vegetables, you know,
like to your point, you can point the Tessl agent at your repo,
at your PR history, at your tickets, slack anything you want.
And it's its whole job is to be able to extract this context
and capture it for you so that, yes, it is a bit of a
you're not just clicking a button and getting code review,
but you're not sitting down and spending three weeks getting your whole team to.
It's like, look at our code review comments from the last three months,
write a document
that captures our code review standards, and then we'll just evolve it from there.
Right.
It's very easy to get going and then improve over time.
And that's where loops come in.
Hey everyone!
Hope you're enjoying the episode so far.
Our team is working really hard behind the scenes to bring you the best guests,
so we can have the most informative conversations about agentic development,
whether that's talking about the latest
tools, the most efficient workflows, or defining best practices.
But for whatever reason, many of you have yet to subscribe to the channel.
If you're enjoying the podcast and want us to continue to bring you
the very best content,
please do us a favor and hit that subscribe button.
It really does make a difference and lets us continue to improve
the quality of our guests and build an even better product for you.
All right, back to the episode.
So maybe let me say a few words about loops
and we'll dive
into specifically code review which we launched as a dedicated loops.
An example one of multiple examples of how to how to build a good loop.
But maybe say a few words about that.
So what we've observed
is we work with customers, we help them create very good context.
But the reality is that companies kind of evolve their practices.
And if you're not, if not creating loops, if you're not creating a factory,
you're not really benefiting from creating this sort of
well crafted piece of context. Right.
Or these great skills,
because you might not be equipped to, to tap the benefit of them.
And so we've been building and I think this was the inception
to kind of create the Tessl agent says like, hey,
let's let's help you create those loops as well.
And the loops will demonstrate that a code reviews an example.
We'll dig into define what correct is, evolve
that, improve that as a skill, get better code review.
But then you know many automations that happen
within within the system that really should be done recurrently.
And we have been building sort of two types of maintenance loops on it.
One is a maintenance loop for your software.
Can you find flaky tests and fix them?
Can you review architecture on a recurring basis?
Can you indeed get test coverage of it?
Can you just handle dependency upgrades?
And so all of those are examples of loops that can be skill driven,
that the Tessl agent can very easily set up for you, and then you can go on
to optimize and improve. And it's not hard.
It's not a it's not a big lift for an organization to come in.
You don't need to be afraid of that sort of factory.
Worker one at a time. Exactly.
You can kind of increment your way there, always skill based.
So you always kind of own your sort of heart and your.
Core and in fact can start manually at first.
Make sure it works, run the skill a couple of times, then turn it into.
A loop. Yeah, precisely. And you can pull it back out of it.
So you very much are kind of in the, in the driver's seat and, and you,
you kind of build out of those now the sort of optimization loop.
And so the, the, the Tessl agent will help you set up the skill and run it.
But what you also need behind the scenes, which is a little bit invisible or like,
you know, like might not be trivial, is that once you start running,
you need a few of these fundamentals.
You need to be able to run the skill
in, in a way that captures the logs of what has been executed.
You want a central place in which you can modify the model,
for instance, and say, okay, now I want to run it with a different model.
So if I ran a bunch of evals and now I know that
I can run it with a cheap model or whatever it is, I can run
that, I can I can modify that relatively easily.
And so all of those, you know, the Tessl projects,
like a bunch of that infrastructure sort of supports creating those.
Loops. And running them.
And I want to stress that we still see the world as skill centric.
Eventually.
What the loop does is it hones a skill, right?
It creates a very good skill,
maybe a harness around it, you know, like, again, skill in the broad sense.
Of the word. Right.
But it but but it really kind of hones a skill.
And then you can use it in many places.
You don't just have to use it in the context of that specific loop.
Yeah.
So I think, feel free to correct me on a bunch of these things that I'm doing it,
but maybe we again, this is a very big and kind of confusing world on it.
And so one of the things we're excited
that we launched is around Tessl code review.
Again,
we have some dedicated videos around that which we'll kind of link to in the notes.
But maybe you can say a few words about what
Tessl code review is and maybe using it as a representation of.
A loop.
So I think the core name of the game is that Tessl's code
review tool is effectively our stance on context driven code review
as one loop that you're going to use in a context driven factory.
So we talked about, oh yeah, you get started with code review.
It feels great.
Then you kind of hit a wall.
And you that happened to test.
We had a code review tool. We still love it.
It's still a great tool.
But we found that as we scaled further and further into Factory World,
we were just unable to compound and get to a place where,
like, we were spending less time reviewing code, which was what we wanted.
And so we took a step back and we thought about what's missing.
We came to this idea that first we needed a way to be able
to shift our standards left.
So we wanted the same
things that are happening in code review to be happening at development time.
And also we needed to have faith that like if things
slip through the gap, like slip through the cracks, they will be caught.
And so we wanted automated loops that come up after
code review time and search for things that got lost.
And so we said, we need all of the standards that go into code
review to be documented and separate so that we can use them elsewhere.
So that's probably the core of Tessl's code review, is that it is skill powered.
We call them lenses, just like code
review lenses where you can supply any number of skills.
It doesn't just have to be one that codify some standard of good in your code base.
You can say which files, which file
patterns those lenses apply to, and then,
just like any other code review tool, you'll set it up through a GitHub app.
And basically every time a PR goes up,
the appropriate lenses will be triggered based on the file patterns.
And we'll review your code.
But now it's a it's a set of skills.
And so you can also make those available to the agent while it develops
or in sort of maintenance agents or automated
sort of sweeps of your code base.
So that's a great piece, right.
Like it allows you to reuse it in many places.
It's also now a thing that you own.
It connects to the rest of Tessl's context platform.
So we can help you evaluate your code, review skill, optimize it, share it across
repos for different different teams, and then importantly, it also
starts
to feed back into the context platform.
So that was another thing that we learned is that code
review is a very rich source of what's going wrong.
Like what skills are we missing, what skills aren't working.
And so as code review is running, it's not just making code
review better, it's making the context of your code base better.
So it's looking for missing context or skills
that maybe aren't being triggered or aren't having the effect
that you'd like,
and suggesting ways to improve them so that they don't have to be caught
at code review time later.
And that kind of gets to
your point of you really want these things to be integrated with one another.
Like you, you don't want your context for development and your code review
standards to be separate.
You want them to feed back into each other to create compounding gains.
And so that's really what the Tessl code review sort of philosophy is.
Yeah.
And I think I think a lot of the analogies to humans.
Right.
Like the the developers on the team do a peer review.
Sort of like the knowledge that they have available to them
when they review is the same knowledge that they have. As.
They build.
And the loop is the example of someone having kind of received a comment,
right, having kind of. Gotten some.
Some bit of. Feedback in the.
Review and then internalize that and come.
Back and, and said.
Why don't we make a standard for this or document.
Exactly. It sort of capture that.
So the next person coming along, you know, sort of driving it.
And so for us, it's not the next person, it's the next agent. Yeah.
But coming along has that knowledge and I really like it.
And I you know, I think reviewing is a critical part of it.
But I guess I think of our code review in comparison to sort of the generic
and powerful code review tools that are out there,
is that I think the key difference is that you own it.
It's your skills, it's your tunings.
You can therefore kind of refine them to your specific needs,
not just what it looks for, but also choices like depth
of scanning and choice of how much do you spend on different models on it.
And we've done some interesting research around that, so you own it.
The second is, that, you know, because of that
sort of refinement and doing it, it's actually just better.
And we have a bunch of that data.
We've sort of seen it in our system, and I don't think it's because,
you know, we have some sort of like brilliant algorithmic improvement over it.
But this is probably just sort of the side effect of the fact that you own it is
the result is better.
It just sort of finds more issues, it finds them faster, it creates less noise.
And so our team.
Specificity basically is the ruler of all quality.
Like if you can have a very specific task that the agent has clear instructions
on what to do, it's
going to be better than a generic here's how to look for code smells.
Exactly.
And then the third is that it is a path to your factory.
And and and you wanted an increasingly like the
we say code review and we we imagine a pull request.
But in practice if you're performing, if you're kind of running an agent
workflow, right, or a factory that takes a ticket and implements it,
you don't need to wait for it to have been sort of checked in.
So you just sort of take that skill and run the review as part of your factory.
Yeah. And you build that out.
So I guess that sort of leads us.
So we talked about skills and the skill centricity.
We talked about loops that indeed, you know, sort of improve skills
and use them with code reviews and example.
And there's many others you should. Sort of.
Yeah.
You can already do many today and more and more of these sort of cookie cutter
use cases will come out.
And then maybe like, let's conclude with the sort of factory piece.
And factory is admittedly like a more nascent piece for us.
Right.
And I think it's because we're kind of accompanying companies, right,
as they sort of go through this journey.
And so they're sort of more immediate needs of the skills and then the loops.
Now they're getting into that sort of broader factory of it.
And we've we've sort of learned through both kind of this work with customers
and through our own sort of factory building around kind of the the need
for more componentry to be available to kind of make the factory run smooth.
Maybe you can say a few words about that.
Yeah.
So the, the core of it again, we talked about if you have a context
centric factory, I'm going to sound like a broken record on that.
We you want to start with writing down
what the workflow is, what good looks like, what success is.
But basically what we found is that you like that's important,
but you can't stop there, right?
Like having a really great skill that you still have to run manually,
or you have to go paste into all of the various places you want it to be used.
You're not going to get the value that comes from having done the work to
write it down.
And so we found with customers, generally, you now need to provide the rails
or the plumbing to deploy that context and to do more and more work
on your behalf in an automated fashion.
And what we found is basically, once you start getting into this world,
like factory building is really it's more of a continuum.
It's not a final state.
You're not going to say, okay, I've made a few loops, now
I will have a factory, and in two months I'll be done.
It's sort of you're going to keep working on loops until you have so many loops
that most of your work is in maintaining loops and building loops to observe them.
And so it's kind of a continuum, whereas you get more
and more, I guess, to use our term from last, more and more loopy.
Right.
It's going to just sort of transition seamlessly into factory work.
It'll be sort of a blended approach.
And so the first thing that we've built to enable this is an automations platform,
which effectively allows you to take the context that you've created
and deploy it in a way that runs on schedule.
Coming soon will be things like webhooks and more automated triggers.
But the idea here is that you you've done the work
to make the workflow to define a standard.
Automations will now let you say, run
this workflow every night or give it access to.
So a big part of the automations platform is controlling the environment
where it runs.
So you can say this workflow needs slack,
it needs notion, and then it needs to run every Friday.
You can put all that together.
It can run, but it's powered by all of the context tools we already have.
You can evaluate that workflow.
You can pick the cheapest model possible so that you're getting as much
like the best quality, but without overpaying for it, but then importantly.
So that's context on the front half of making the automations actually work.
But on the back half,
the automations platform integrates back into the context platform.
So all of those runs are capturing logs.
You can then create additional automations that review those logs
and make improvements to the skill based on real world usage.
And then, of course, it also integrates into the rest of our context
platform, where all of these automations are multi-player by default.
You can. The same way you can see all of the skills in your repo.
You can see all of the automations that your team has created.
You can share them.
You can create sort of permissions around them.
Yeah, yeah.
And so that's a really exciting way that we're giving users more
ability to use the skills they've created.
So that's a good kind of description of these different services
that that we built to it.
I guess the point I'd emphasize is, you know,
we think every company should own its factory.
In fact, we think there will be a plurality of factories, right?
Like they will have factories for different repos or business units or
sort of segments of it.
And we think a factory is something you should own, right?
Like it is it is your custom definition of what correct is.
It's the new software engineering.
And so it doesn't.
That does not mean that you should build every aspect of it.
And we think that our job as sort of tool providers,
right, as enablers of this sort of agent era
development is, is to give you a bunch
of these things to make it easy to make a bunch of these things simple.
And so a lot of these kind of components, they come out of, of portions
that we think are reusable, whether they are around observability,
whether they're around, of course, everything
to do with context, the capturing of the context,
the assessment of the context, etc., whether it's just
just sort of utilities like scheduling, like, like access controls,
like dashboards and visuals around what makes for kind of
an effective dashboard or like an effective factory or not.
And what should you learn?
So our job is to really consolidate a lot of industry learnings
and our own learnings and kind of repeat work
in various parts of the industry and capture it up.
And so I would say that our our kind
of factory componentry is still relatively light.
There's a world that we still need to build over here,
and that is on purpose because, again, we sort of advance with our
with our customers and many of them, they want to build their own factory.
Some of these things should really be custom built components.
Yeah.
And we'll sort of help them build the the componentry there.
But what we will emphasize maybe once more is that we think
a factory should really be skills centric, context centric.
It should start from your definitions of what correct software development is.
And what we want to be is just like an SDLC platform that has a sequence
of these different components to help you apply your development process.
This is what Tessl is to you to, to help you
kind of build your factory and evolve.
And of course, as always, we're sort of there to
to kind of help you in the process itself, to help you kind of learn and and grow.
Yeah.
So a lot has happened. A lot.
We've been busy.
It's actually been sort of super exciting to have these, these sort of weekly
reviews of what's coming this week of it.
And it's like, okay, these these teams, we have very empowered teams.
They've been building great components, working with customers on it.
And and just like in the next week, it's like,
oh yeah, that's sort of big chunk over here
that maybe like a quarter's work or something like that previous.
It's done. Okay.
What do we do next?
It does feel like you can't blink,
which is sort of a exciting and exciting and daunting at the same time.
so if you found all of this conversation interesting, we'd love
for you to try the sort of the expanded Tessl of it.
Of course, you can always run.
Still, Tessl's skill review and the evals and a lot of these components
that we've been building for a long while, we're very excited and we're seeing
a lot of sort of uptake around the Tessl agent and using it to build loops.
So we'd love that.
And then maybe try out thinking about using Tessl
as the platform to kind of build up a broader context centric.
If it wasn't, if we didn't say that enough context centric.
One. More time factory over it and, you know,
is hopefully, I think is evidenced to anyone that has been tracking us.
We're very, very community oriented.
So we'd love if you try it out, and we'd also love
your perspective on the sort of philosophy that we're espousing here
around our belief that you should build your factory
gradually, going from skills to loops to a factory.
And with that, thanks for tuning in and I hope you join us for the next one.
The AI Native Dev is brought to you by Tessl, the package manager
for skills and context.
Your hosts are Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple.
Our producer is Tom Dowler.
The AI Native Dev is not just a podcast, it's a community.
And we host monthly meetups at the Tessl offices in central London.
Visit tessl.io/community to learn more and I hope to see you there.